<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://replware.dev" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Replware</title><link>https://replware.dev</link><description>Complex web and cloud systems development and consulting. All functional. Clojure, ClojureScript, Datomic.</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 03:50:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://replware.dev/posts-output/2019-07-13-docs/</guid><link>https://replware.dev/posts-output/2019-07-13-docs/</link><title>Web Application Consulting/Development</title><description>&lt;h2 id="services"&gt;Services&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rapid prototyping and MVP&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enterprise software solution&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Datomic Database&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="technology"&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use Clojure, ClojureScript, and Datomic as our primary technical stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="customer&amp;#95;testimonial"&gt;Customer Testimonial&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="why&amp;#95;us?"&gt;Why us?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="you&amp;#95;need&amp;#95;a&amp;#95;consultant&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;clarify&amp;#95;your&amp;#95;problems"&gt;You need a consultant to clarify your problems&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;According the &lt;a href='https://www.projectsmart.co.uk/white-papers/chaos-report.pdf'&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the Standish Group, only 16.2% of software projects are completed on time and on budget. The top three of the project challenged factors are: Lack of user input, incomplete requirements and changing requirements. We understand that the continuous user input is the key to project success. That is why our working process is like this: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Requirement: Discuss with our customer about requirements.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Execute: Implement the software.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People: Let the people to use our software. Customers will understand the essence of problems more through the interaction with half-completed software.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loop: Loop the whole process again.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can run our REPL process with the frequency once every week. Through our REPL process, our customer can incrementally express their requirement naturally, which also contributes to the high success rate of our projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="you&amp;#95;need&amp;#95;correct,&amp;#95;well-tested&amp;#95;software"&gt;You need correct, well-tested software&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a program in possession of good quality, must be well-tested. With Clojure as our primary programming language, every expression is tested through the REPL environment. This is not the granularity of unit test, but the granularity of expression test. In addition, REPL-driven development is not like test-driven development that programmers need to invest a certain amount of time on writing tests. We deliver well-tested software without slowing down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="you&amp;#95;need&amp;#95;immutable&amp;#95;database"&gt;You need immutable database&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider that you have an RDBMS database with an order table inside. Last week, there was a lot of orders inserted, and you could query the database to get the revenue last week. This week, some orders updated, and you can still query the database to get the revenue this week. What if you forget the revenue number last week, and you want to reproduce the revenue from the database? You can not make it because certain orders have been updated. With Datomic, the immutable database, you can easily get the last week revenue by simply asking the database to go back to the state last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="contact"&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/img/mail.png" alt="Email" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>